# Ing. Roman Ožana / Resume

Hi there,

my name is Roman Ožana. I am a freelance webdesigner and developer with **more than 10 years of experiences**. I'm here to create websites and applications easy to use, intuitive and modern inside. I love tech startups and community around. Enjoy working in small and effective team.

Say hi on Twitter @OzzyCzech

• Address: Prague, Přímětická st.

• Web: omdesign.cz

Email: <u>ozana@omdesign.cz</u>
Phone: <u>+420 605 783 455</u>



## **Working Experiences**

<u>Testomato s.r.o.</u> – Co-founder & main developer

March 2012 - present

Devel.cz Lab s.r.o. - PHP/JS developer

October 2009 – present

Work as PHP/JS developer and web designer mostly on zdrojak.cz

omdesign.cz – Freelance web designer

October 2009 - present

Freelance web designer and developer of Internet application – mostly in PHP/Javascript.

7 years 4 months

8 years 2 months 1 day

10 years 5 months 1 day

## Former Working Experiences

Intergraph s.r.o. - Application Engineer

July 2010 - April 2011

Application Engineer (external consultant) – testing of corporate solution for metadata sharing and managing. Developing of simple C# .NET applications.

Skvely.CZ s.r.o. – PHP developer

March 2009 - July 2010

Works there as web application developer mostly in PHP and developing some modules for e-commerce Magento.

9 months

1 year 5 months

## **Skills & Technologies**

#### Day-to-day comfort

- PHP
- · OOP, DI, IOC, design patterns
- SQL language (MariaDB, MySQL)
- · MySQL, Redis, MongoDB, Memcached
- Javascript ES6
- React, Angular, jQuery
- HTML5, CSS3 (incl. LESS, Sass, cssnext, PostCSS)
- Webpack 4 & Makefile
- · Responsive Layout and Design
- · Basics of Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator

#### Quality assurance

- E2E testing with Protractor
- Selenium + Selenium IDE
- Unit Testing (PHP Unit, Nette Tester, Mocha)

#### Experience with

- · React, NextJS
- · Node.js
- · Gulp & Grunt
- Couchbase

#### DevStack

- Docker
- · Git version control
- · Webpack, Makefile
- Travis & GitLab CI
- · MacOS and Linux

## Languages

- Czech native language
- English communicative

#### **Additional Info**

· Driving license: B

#### **Education**

#### VŠB - Technical University of Ostrava

2002 - 2007: Geoinformatics

- Study program: Geodesy and cartography, Geoinformatics
- Degree: Master's degree (Msc., Geoingormatics)
- Address: VŠB Technical university of Ostrava, 17. listopadu 15, Ostrava Poruba, Faculty of Mining and Geology

#### SPŠE Rožnov pod Radhoštěm

1997 – 2001: Electronic computer systems

GitHub: https://github.com/OzzyCzech/

**StackOverflow:** https://meta.stackoverflow.com/users/355316/

Twitter: https://www.twitter.com/OzzyCzech